patrickmcmullan.com 2013-11-05

# Patrick McMullan Company

**PATRICK MCMULLAN COMPANY PRIVACY POLICY**

Patrick McMullan Company (“PMc”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy tells you about our online collection and use of data. The terms of this policy apply to all PMc websites, unless different terms are specified in a form or contract provided to you online or offline. 

By using this site, you understand and agree to the terms of this policy. This site is owned by PMc and may be accessed in the United States and abroad. For data protection purposes, PMc is the controller and, unless otherwise noted, is also the processor of data. Information collected may be retained, and may be stored, processed, accessed, and used in jurisdictions whose privacy laws may be different and less protective than those of your home jurisdiction. 

**Collection of Your Personal Information**

When you use our website, we may collect "non-personal information." We consider "non-personal information" to be information that, by itself, cannot be used to identify or contact you personally, such as demographic information (your age, gender, income, education, profession, etc.). Non-personal information may also include technical information, such as your IP address, the type of browser you are using, the websites you visit immediately before and immediately after you visit our website, and other anonymous data involving your use of our website. Non-personal information may also include information that you provide us through your use of our website, such as the terms you enter into the search functions of our website. We reserve the right to use or disclose non-personal information in any way we see fit.

We may combine your visit and navigational information with personal information that you provide. You may always choose not to provide personal information, but if you so choose, certain products and services may not be available to you. Personal information (e.g., your username and password, your name, your mailing address, email address, and phone number) is collected when you register. Additional personal information (e.g., your credit card number and billing address) is collected to process transactions or to provide you with products and services. 

**Use of Your Personal Information**

PMc collects and uses your personal information to operate and improve our sites, to process your transactions, to provide customer service, to perform research and analysis aimed at improving our products, services and technologies, and to display content that is customized to your interests and preferences. 

We also use your personal information to communicate with you. We may send transaction-related communications such as welcome letters, billing reminders, and purchase confirmations. We may also send you surveys or marketing communications to inform you of new products or services or other information that may be of interest. If you do not wish to receive marketing communications, you may follow the “unsubscribe” instructions included within each email communication. 

Personal information collected by PMc may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which PMc or its affiliates, subsidiaries, contractors or agents maintain facilities, and by using our sites or services, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.  If you would like to exercise any of your data protection rights (including the right to have your personal information deleted), please contact us using the “Contact Information” below. 

**Sharing of Your Personal Information**

Except as disclosed in this privacy policy, PMc does not share your personal information with any outside parties. 

We may share your personal information within our corporate group, including with our subsidiaries and divisions, all of whom may use your information for the purposes disclosed herein.

Information about our customers, including personal information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, acquisition, or sale of the company and/or its assets, as well as in the unlikely event of insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, in which personal information would be transferred as one of the business assets of the company. We will notify you of such an occurrence as described in the “Changes to This Privacy Policy” section below. 

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process, respond to claims, or protect the rights, property or safety of our company, employees, customers, or the public.

**Service Providers**

We sometimes engage unaffiliated businesses to assist us in providing you certain services. For example, we may use third parties to provide advertising, marketing and promotional assistance, provide email services, or facilitate our online services. In those instances, we may need to share your personal information with them. We require these companies to use your personal information only to provide the particular product or service and do not authorize them to use your personal information for any other reason.

We sometimes offer promotions in conjunction with a third party sponsor. If you choose to participate in one of those promotions, we may share your information with the sponsor if they need it to send you a product or other special promotion they offer.

**Third Party Advertisers**

We use third-party advertising companies to deliver specific advertisements to you, which appear on pages throughout our website. These companies collect non-personal information about your visits to our website and other websites in order to provide advertisements about products and services that may be of interest to you. These companies may also aggregate your non-personal information for use in targeted advertising, marketing research, and other similar purposes. These companies may place their own cookies on your computer. If you want to prevent a third-party advertiser from collecting and using this information, you may visit each third party advertiser's website directly and opt-out.

**Accessing Your Personal Information**

If you would like to review or revise information that you previously provided to us, you may access your information in the “My Account” section of the website. If you need additional assistance, please contact us at info@patrickmcmullan.com. You can expect a response from us within 10 calendar days. Please be advised that you cannot change your username without re-registering. 

**Personal Information Preferences**

PMc respects your right to make choices about the use and disclosure of your personal information. If at any time you decide that you do not want to receive marketing communications from us, please let us know by: (1) checking or unchecking the appropriate box on your online registration form or the “My Account” page of the website; (2) contacting your Account Executive; or (3) sending an email to info@patrickmcmullan.com. 

**Use of Cookies**

We may use "cookies" to enhance your visits to our website. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies do not store personal information about you, unless you knowingly provide it. Cookies can store non-personal information, such as what websites, pages, or advertisements your browser has accessed. We may use cookies to store information and personalize your experience with our website. For example, cookies allow our website to recognize your browser as a previous visitor, and thus save and remember any preferences that may have been set while you were previously browsing our website. Our cookies can also store your password, personalize pages, and keep track of selections, such as your time zone and episode selections.

You do have control over cookies. Most browsers can be set to notify you when a cookie is being placed on your computer. Most browsers can also be set to refuse to accept cookies, although this may affect your Internet experience. You can also erase cookies that are already on your computer. For more information about working with cookies, you should consult your user manual, FAQ, or "help" function of your specific browser and operating system software.

In some cases, our third-party service providers may use cookies on our sites. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by PMc only, and does not cover the use of cookies by third parties.

**Web Beacons**

We also may use "web beacons" (also often referenced as "clear GIFs", "clear pixels", "web bugs", "1x1 GIFs", or "1x1 pixels") which are tiny graphic image files, imbedded in a web page in GIF, jpeg or HTML format, that provide a presence on the web page and send back to its home server information from your browser, such as the IP address, the URL of the page on which the web beacon is located, the type of browser that is accessing the site and the ID number of any cookies on your computer previously placed by that server. We may use web beacons to collect non-personal information about your use of our website and the websites of selected sponsors and advertisers, and your use of special promotions or newsletters. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our website and selected sponsors' and advertisers' sites. Our web beacons are not used to track your activity outside of our website or those of our sponsors. We do not link non-personal information from web beacons to personally identifiable information without your permission.

**Security of Your Personal Information**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to secure your personal information. However, there is always some risk in transmitting information electronically. The personal information we collect is stored within databases that we control. As we deem appropriate, we use security measures consistent with industry standards, such as firewalls and encryption technology, to protect your information. However, we cannot guarantee the security of our databases, nor can we guarantee that information you supply won't be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

If a password is used to protect your account and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. 

**Forums & Other Interactive Services**

Our websites may include discussion forums or other interactive areas or services, including blogs, chat rooms, bulletin boards, message boards, online hosting or storage services, or other areas or services in which you or third parties create, post or store any content, messages, comments, materials or other items on the sites (“Interactive Areas”). If you use an Interactive Area, you should be aware that these areas are open to the public and any personal information you post or provide at registration may be viewable by others. We are not responsible for personal information you submit in connection with the Interactive Areas, nor are we responsible for how others might use that information, including to send you unsolicited messages. Interactive Area postings may be retained indefinitely. If at any time you would like to remove a posting, please email us at info@patrickmcmullan.com.  Keep in mind that removal of a posting from an Interactive Area does not mean that the posting will be deleted from our systems. 

**Children**

We do not intend to solicit or collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are under 18, you should not use or enter information on this site, including without limitation, any Interactive Areas of the site. 

**Links**

We may link to websites, including those of our third-party content providers, who have different privacy policies and practices from those disclosed here. We assume no responsibility for the policies or practices of such linked sites, and encourage you to become acquainted with them prior to use. 

**Accuracy of the Information We Collect**

Any questions you may have regarding this policy, the accuracy of your personal information or the use of your personal information, or any requests that we correct, update, or remove your information in our databases, should be directed via email to info@patrickmcmullan.com, or via regular mail to:

Patrick McMullan Company, Inc.  
321 West 14th Street, #B  
New York, NY  10014

After receiving a request to change your information, we will make reasonable efforts to ensure that all of your personal information stored in databases we actively use to operate our website will be updated, corrected, changed or deleted, as appropriate, as soon as reasonably practicable. However, we reserve the right to retain in our archival files any information we remove from or change in our active website databases. We may retain such information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our terms and conditions of use. In addition, it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to us. A copy of your personal information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate. 

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this policy at any time, and will post any changes to this policy as soon as they go into effect. You are bound by any minor changes to the policy when you use the site after those changes have been posted. Please refer back to this policy on a regular basis. If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify by posting a notice on our website for 30 days.

**Contact Information**

You can contact PMc by emailing info@patrickmcmullan.com, or by postal mail at Patrick McMullan Company, Inc., 321 West 14th Street, #B, New York, NY 10014.
